Good Morning, Church!
Turn to your neighbour and greet them, "Good Morning!"
Give your neighbour a handshake and say, "Good Morning!"
Give your other neighbour a handshake and say, "Good Morning!"
Give the neighbour behind you a handshake and say, "Good Morning!"
Give the neighbour in front of you a handshake and say, "Good Morning!"
And greet the viewers all over the world on Emmanuel TV, "Good Morning!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now, turn to your neighbour and greet them, "Merry Christmas!"
Give your neighbour a handshake and say, "Merry Christmas!"
Give your other neighbour a handshake and say, "Merry Christmas!"
Give the neighbour behind you a handshake and say, "Merry Christmas!"
Give the neighbour in front of you a handshake and say, "Merry Christmas!"
And greet the viewers all over the world on Emmanuel TV,
"Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year in advance!"
Glory be to God! You are all welcome to the presence of God, in Jesus' name.
Right now, you may have your seats.
My name is Brother Chris, by the grace of God.
I'm from the UK.
I thank God for the wonderful privilege and honour to be here in your midst today.
I thank God for the life of His servant Prophet T.B. Joshua
who God used to mentor me, to guide me, to be in your midst this morning
to proclaim the wonderful news of our Lord Jesus Christ.
Thank You, Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now, it is just two days to Christmas.
Tell your neighbour, "Merry Christmas!"
Like I mentioned before, I'm from the UK.
In the UK, we take Christmas very seriously - it is a serious issue.
Unfortunately, we don't take Christ very seriously.
I wish we would take Christ as seriously as we take Christmas.
But nevertheless, Christmas, we take it very seriously in the UK.
I believe around the world - different cultures, customs, communities -
we have our way of celebrating Christmas.
In the UK, we have many traditions and ceremonies attached to Christmas.
I just want to share with you a very quick story.
This is a true story - Christmas story.
Just to set the tone for today's message.
Now, one of the traditions on Christmas in the UK is that we have nativity plays.
Do you know what I mean by that?
In your school, the children will reenact the story of Jesus
when Jesus was born - it is called a nativity play.
Every year, without fail, your school must hold that nativity play
where they have Mary and Joseph and baby Jesus.
They go to the inn, they say, "There is no room in the inn".
They are taken finally to the manger, the stable.
She gives birth to baby Jesus.
We all know the story of Christmas.
We all know the story of Jesus.
Now, picture this. This was a nativity play that I attended.
These were little children.
It got to the part of the story where the sheperds and the wise men came to see Jesus
at the manger when he had just been born.
You guys know the story very well.
You know the story well?
Good. So I don't need to repeat to you the details of the story.
It got to the part where the three wise men who had travelled thousands of miles
to come and honour Jesus who had just been born.
They came to present their gifts.
Just picture this.
Three little kids are the three wise men, dressed in their robes and regalia to show they are wise men.
The first one walks forward and says, "We are wise men to see Jesus.
Here is the gift of gold".
Drops the gold; then walks back.
The second wise man comes forward - "And myrrh."
Drops it; walks back.
The third wise man, the little boy walks forward.
And he forgets his line.
I don't know whether you have ever been in that moment; it's very painful.
You know the family, the parents, everyone is there watching.
And the little boy just forgot his line.
Everyone was trying to - "Will you remember..."
Trying to get him remember the line.
The boy was worried; he was scared.
Everybody was tense.
In Nigeria, we would say, "Wahala don't come". That is the situation.
Everyone was tense, worried, "What is going to happen?"
Suddenly, the little boy remembered.
With a smile, he walks forward and says, "And Frank sent this".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you with me?
He walked forward, he forgot the line and said, "And Frank sent this".
Instead of "frankincense".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now, I'm just trying to set the scene for today's message, the Christmas message.
But on a more serious note:
Today, we so often celebrate the tradition and ceremony of Christmas
and our focus is more on the story of the Baby Jesus, the story of the Christ of history,
the story of the Christ of song, the Christmas carols
and we overlook the reason for Christmas.
So I want to encourage you today:
Don't get so carried away by the ceremony of Christmas that you forget the reason for Christmas.
We should never allow the tradition of Christmas to overshadow our relationship with Jesus
because Jesus is the centre of Christmas.
Say, "Neighbour, Jesus is the centre of Christmas".
Without Jesus, there would be no Christmas.
Viewers around the world, today, we want to celebrate Jesus at Christmas.
Not just the Baby Jesus or the Christ of history, story, song,
the one we sing about in the Christmas carols.
We want to celebrate Jesus Christ revealed by the Holy Spirit.
And this will bring us to the title of today's message:
O COME LET US ADORE HIM
Say, "Neighbour, Christmas is all about Jesus".
Now, you may have observed that the title of today's message
comes from a very well known Christmas carol.
You know the song, "O come let us adore Him"?
I'm not hearing you; do you know it?
[Yes.]
Alright because we are going to sing it right now. Let's give it a go.
O come let us adore Him
Christ the Lord
Put your hands together for yourselves.
Put your hands together.
Let's just try this - men first; all the men, are you ready?
All the men - are you ready?
Ok, let's go.
O come let us adore Him
Christ the Lord
Alright, the women now; the females - let's go.
O come let us adore Him
Christ the Lord
Put your hands together for Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may then have your seats in the presence of God.
I love the simple melody and the simple words, the simple truth of that carol.
O come let us adore Him
It's all about Jesus.
Today, the world is trying to commercialise Christmas.
They want to turn it to be about shopping, food and fun; just festivities.
Yet, Christmas is about those things but more importantly, it's about Jesus.
It's not about you, it's not about us - it's all about Him.
Unfortunately, many people when they sing that carol, in their hearts, there is a different song.
Some hearts are singing: "O come let us adore me.
O come let us adore me. Chris the Lord".
Why? - Because they are so focused on themselves.
Christmas to them is all about how they can enjoy the flesh,
enjoy the material things of this world.
Once again, brethren, I want to redirect your focus to who Christmas is all about -
it's all about Jesus.
If there was ever a time to celebrate and to acknowledge
and to revisit the love of God for us, this is the time.
So turn with me in your Bibles to the Book of 1 John 4.
We just want to use this Christmas season
as an opportunity to remind ourselves of how much Jesus loves us.
1 John 4:9 and it says:
"This is how God showed His love among us:
He sent His one and only Son into the world that we might live through Him."
Verse 10.
"This is love: not that we loved God,
but that He loved us and His Son as an atoning sacrifice for our sins.
Dear friends, since God so loved us, we also ought to love one another."
Now.
In today's world, in our generation today,
if you look at the crises, the trouble, the turmoil in the world,
many people ask themselves the question, "Does God really love me?"
And that is one of satan's tactics.
One of satan's tactics is to try and get you to doubt God's love and goodness.
You begin to say, "All the trouble going on in the world, the evil happening,
the terrible things that are taking place" -
you just look around you, there is so much trouble,
there is political trouble, economic trouble, religious trouble.
I mean, we are in a world that is full of trouble.
And because of that, many hearts have grown cold to Jesus.
Many people's love has grown cold; their hearts have been hardened.
They become cynical, sceptical when it comes to Jesus or the things of God.
"You live, let me live.
I live my life, you live your life because look at what is happening in the world.
Where is God in the midst of this? Where is God in the midst of the sorrow?
Where is God in the midst of the trouble? Where is God in the midst of the trials?"
So, viewers, I want to encourage you today and challenge you today.
I don't know what situation you may be facing
that may be causing you to doubt God's love.
Perhaps, you are facing relentless troubles, hurtful hard times.
Perhaps, you are facing hatred, hunger or homelessness.
Perhaps, it is painful persecution.
You may be facing betrayal by your friends, family.
Or worse yet, your own awful sin.
But one thing I do know, one thing I'm assured of:
There is nothing, not one thing that is evil enough,
ugly enough, deep enough, powerful enough to stop God from loving you.
Nothing!
Nothing anyone could do to you could possibly sever that connection,
could dam the unstoppable, undeniable, unconditional love of God.
You can ignore God, you can reject Him, you can slander Him
but His love for you remains constant and unchanging.
No matter how many times we fail, God's love never does.
No matter how many times we fall, God's love never does.
No matter how many times we falter, God's love never does.
Apostle Paul said, "I am convinced that neither death nor life,
neither angels nor demons, neither the past nor the present, neither height nor depth,
nothing in this world can separate me from the love of God which is in Christ Jesus, my Lord".
Say, "Neighbour, God loves you as much as He does any of His children".
He loves you. Some of us begin to say, "Maybe God chose partiality;
this guy - He loves him more than me. He is showing favouritism". No!
The Father has no favourites.
There are no lucky ones in the Lord, no pets of Divinity.
He loves us.
Some people may be saying, "Why? How can we reconcile the two -
the troubles and the turmoil in the world and a loving, good God?"
I want to assure you, brethren.
God has not left us, abandoned us or closed the door on us;
we are the ones that have left Him.
God has not left us; He is with us.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
That is our greeting in The SCOAN.
The question is: Are you with Him?
Because we easily stray from God and then question Him when our lives begin to go up and down.
Once again, brethren, this Christmas season is an opportunity
for you to realise how much God loves you.
God so loved the world that He gave His only Son.
Prophet T.B. Joshua explains, "God has a Son and He planted Him in the earth
to produce a family.
Today, millions are born again because of His best Seed".
That is why we are here today in the presence of God, celebrating His birth.
Millions are born-again because of His best Seed.
God gave us His best at Christmas.
Love was born at Christmas.
When you celebrate the birth of Jesus at Christmas, you are celebrating His love,
His joy, faithfulness, goodness, forgiveness.
Remember, by His love, we love.
In His love, we have a newness of life.
Through His love, we become a new man.
Jesus came to restore that relationship and fellowship between God and man.
That is why He came.
I want to challenge you today; it is a two-pronged message.
It is both a reminder of how much God loves you
and as a challenge to ask yourself, "How much do you love Him?"
What is your relationship with Him like?
The main thing about Christianity is not the work we do,
is not the services we attend, the prayers we pray,
the tithes, the offerings we drop.
I'm not saying they are not part of Christianity; they are all good but that is not the main thing.
The main thing about Christianity is not the work we do but the relationship we maintain
and the atmosphere produced by that relationship.
This means that nothing is more important than our relationship with Jesus.
Say, "Neighbour, nothing is more important than my relationship with Jesus".
Ask yourself today, "Is there anything in your life that is more important than Jesus?"
Just challenge yourself, "Is there anything in my life that is more important than Jesus?"
Jesus was asked in Matthew 22, "What is the greatest commandment?"
Jesus responded, "Love the Lord your God with all your heart,
all your mind, all your soul and all your strength".
Love God above all.
That is the summary of the Scriptures.
Love Him above all.
This Christmas, challenge yourself.
As you go about celebrating the birth of Jesus,
ask yourself, "Do I love God above all or is He just one of those things that are important to me?"
God is the only reason; not one of these things.
I'm going to try and very simply do an example to practicalise this.
Let me get four volunteers.
One volunteer from here - any one volunteer.
Any one volunteer, you can just come forward.
Alright, sir, thank you very much.
Sir, you come and stand here.
I need one volunteer from here.
Our brother is instantly ready. You stand here.
I need another volunteer from here.
If God puts it in your heart, just come out.
Brilliant. That is three.
One more from here.
Ok, you can just come out. Wonderful.
So this is a very simple example and I want you to question yourself.
You sir, congratulations, you are going to represent God.
Thank You, Jesus.
God is "Thank You, Jesus" - wonderful.
Our brother is going to represent God; it's a wonderful role.
You sir, it is still a good role but not quite up to God.
You are going to represent Mr Money.
You are Mr Money, okay?
Okay.
Okay, wonderful.
Here is Mr Money - money.
You sir, are going to represent Mr Social Relations - friends, family, well-wishers, etc.
You sir, are going to represent Mr Position.
So we have God, we have Mr Money,
we have Mr Social Relations and we have Mr Position.
Are you with me, people of God?
I'm not hearing you - are you with me, people of God?
[Yes!]
Ok, so come, sir.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
First of all, I want to show you how a Christian life should look.
God is not one of these things.
You can't compare Him to position, you can't compare Him to friends or family and
you can't compare Him to money.
God is not one of these things.
God is the only thing, the only reason.
Jesus is THE Way, not a way.
So in my journey through life, let's just say, I meet Mr Money here.
And Mr Money offers me some investment advice.
Sir, just tell me about a proposal that will involve money.
I want to give you 10 million US dollars, what are you going to do with it?
Wow, thank You, Jesus! 10 million! This is awesome!
Now, as a Christian, do you know what I'm supposed to do?
Immediately I hear from Mr Money, what do I do?
I go back to God and confirm from Him the step to take!
Because you just hear the money - 10 million - but God is concerned about the source.
Does that money come from stealing?
Does that money come from corruption?
Is that money blood money?
If I take it and it comes from stealing, I will use it for stealing.
Whatever comes from stealing, goes to stealing.
Whatever comes from corruption, goes to corruption.
Whatever comes from blood, goes to blood.
Are you with me?
So, what do I do?
As a Christian, I am meant to love God above all.
The meaning of this is - love nothing in comparison of God
but everything in reference to God.
So my brother offers me 10 million dollars. Wonderful.
What do I do? - I go back to God.
What does God say? What is God's opinion?
What is His will? What is His will in this matter?
And there will be guidance and direction, and you won't make a mistake.
I go to my brother here, Mr Social Relations.
Just invite me to a party, sir.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I will send him all kinds of friends - friends from everywhere.
Merci. (Thank you.)
Wonderful. This is a multilingual example here. Praise God.
My friend is inviting me; he said there is a party which has a lot of these friends;
my family will be there.
As a Christian, what am I supposed to do?
Nothing in comparison of God; everything in reference to God.
What does God say?
This party - is it a place where Jesus will be welcomed?
The activities there - are they in line with God?
Are they going to be serving and selling things that contradict my faith?
If I go there, am I going to be exposed to things that will pollute my spirit?
Carry God along.
As a Christian.
I'm going to Mr Position. Sir, you can just offer me a position.
I'm offering you the CEO position of a multinational company.
Wow! CEO!
Look, don't get carried away.
Don't begin to say, "Yes, sir" instantly. "I will be there tomorrow, sir."
What do you do as a Christian?
You go to God.
What does God say?
What is His will? What is His opinion?
Nothing in comparison of God; everything in reference to Him.
That is a Christian who loves God above all.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
But many of us today...
Come, sir.
Many of us today - you know the problem we have?
Just stand here.
The problem we have today is that we see God as one of those thigns.
Yes, money is important to me; my friends, family are important to me.
My job, position; God too is important to me.
No!
How can you equate God, the Creator with the created?
How can you begin to put God at the same level with these material possessions?
But this is what many of us do.
By the time my brother here offers me that 10 million dollars,
I will seek some advice.
I will say, "God, want do you say about the 10 million dollars?"
It is nothing before me.
God says, it is nothing before Him.
He is saying, "Look, don't be too much in a haste and rush to take that money".
But I say, "Look, before I just listen to God, let me ask Position.
Maybe Mr Position has something to say.
What do you want to say about the 10 million dollars?
It is good money.
You begin to say, "Oh, this is difficult.
God is saying, maybe I shouldn't but look, Position is saying, it is good.
My friends, my family, they are going to agree.
10 million dollars - they will enjoy from that.
Money, of course, is offering it to me.
You begin to have confusion, conflict because you have equated God with the created.
Tell your neighbour, "Check yourself".
Now, this is not even the worst part of it.
Do you know the worst part of it?
Many of us today have not only put God as one of those things,
we have actually picked another God.
Come, sir.
Some of us have put Mr Money in the position of God.
You know, Christmas is a time to give, a time to love, a time to share.
God may speak to your heart and tell you to go and help someone.
"Go and take care of an orpan."
Just tell me to go and look after someone, sir.
Go and look after someone.
Take care of him.
Now, God has spoken to your heart.
There is an orphan; there is a homeless child. Go and look after them.
But do you know what many of us do?
"Let me quickly check with money.
Let me ask Mr Money first."
What is he going to say?
I want you to quit Christianity.
Wow. Money even wants me to quit Christianity. Crazy.
But in this case, money can never advise you to start helping people without an instant gain.
Money will want to see you put something and get something out.
You can't just go and help someone with no one there to give you back.
The principles of money do not permit that.
God is the one that will cause you and ask you to sow to the Spirit.
You will help someone without any return -
you sow to the Spirit; you reap peace of heart.
But money will say, "No! How can you waste your money on that?
There are investment here, there are investments there".
We have now put money, position, friends in the place of God.
We do everything in reference to money.
God may say, "Go here"; you say, "Let me quickly confirm from my family".
My family says, "Don't do it"; I say, "God, sorry. My family said I cannot go".
You put your family above God.
I'm not saying you should not love your family; I'm not saying we don't need money;
I'm not saying there is no good position.
I'm talking of what is your priority,
what is number 1 in your life.
God gave His best for you at Christmas.
Have you given your best to Him?
Let me round up this example. Come, sir.
Do you know one thing?
Sooner or later, you will realise this truth.
Money can fail you.
What you invested in for years can be gone in seconds.
Friends, family - they can fail you.
The person that is smiling at your front today can stab you in the back tomorrow.
The person you love - they can die, they can leave you tomorrow, they can fail you.
Position can fail you.
You have seen people who have been at the top today; tomorrow, they are at the bottom.
Only Jesus will never fail you!
Why would you then compare Him to this?
Oh my God!
What is going on?
Put your trust in money, man and materials - you are doomed to disappointment.
Put your trust in Jesus - you will never be confounded in time or eternity.
He is Alpha and Omega, beginning and end, first and last, the I AM that I AM.
He is God, Creator.
And you know one thing about God?
Let me tell you a truth about God.
As you are busy trying to please money, trying to please man,
trying to woo sympathy to gain position, God is just looking at you
because Prophet T.B. Joshua says, Jesus is a democrat;
He does not impose Himself on anyone.
He will not force you to follow Him.
He will not beg you to believe in Him.
He will not force you to serve Him.
He will wait.
By the time you have exhausted your worldly advantages -
you tried money, it failed you, you tried man that disappointed you,
you tried position, you don't have peace.
By the time you have exhausted your worldly advantages, you will come back to God
and at that time, you will value Him and put Him where He belongs -
put Him as number one, the first place.
And I pray you won't have grey hairs by the time you do that
because many of us are wasting so much time on Mr Money,
trying to please Mr Money, woo Mr Money, getting Mr Money's attention.
I'm not saying money is not good.
If this man gives me 10 million and I go to God and God sees it is clean and clear,
it is a blessing from Him, go ahead - "Thank You, Jesus!"
I'm talking about what is first in your life.
Today, if many of us received a call that 10 million dollars are waiting,
you would quickly tell the usher, "I'm going to the toilet".
From the toilet, you are gone.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, this Christmas, love God above all".
O COME LET US ADORE HIM
Alright. Thank you very much to my wonderful actors.
You can come and take an altar fruit
so we can move on to a new life.
Mr Money will now give His life completely to Jesus.
Mr Position...
Wow.
This is altar fruit but because he is God, we cannot query him.
He should go ahead.
May God query him.
Now brethren, this is what Jesus meant in Matthew 6:33 when He said,
"Seek first the Kingdom of God and His righteousness
and then everything else will be added unto you".
Today, we want to seek everything else; expect the Kingdom to follow.
But Jesus said, "Seek first the Kingdom of God and His righteousness
and then everything else will be added unto you".
Today, so many of us want to see Jesus but we are not prepared to seek Him.
We want to see Him but we are not ready to seek Him.
We want to see His miracles but we are not ready to seek His ways.
We want to see His power; we are not ready to seek His character.
We want to see Him but we are not prepared to seek Him.
Wise men still seek Jesus.
Wise women still seek Jesus.
Just as it was in the time when Jesus was born and the wise men came.
In our generation, wise men still seek Jesus.
If you just come to church today and you are just here for a miracle,
"God give me a miracle; give me blessing!",
I want to advise you this Christmas.
Stop seeking a miracle; start seeking Jesus and the miracle will come.
You know that God wants the best for you.
Christmas demonstrates that; He wants the best for you.
Why can't you trust Him, put Him first
and He will give you what His best for you in His time, in His way, for His glory?
Let's round up this message; coming to a conclusion.
If you want the ministry to be strong, your relationship with God must be strong.
I'm not just talking about those in the church - pastors or evangelists - for those in the vineyard. No!
As a Christian, whatever you do through God is your calling - your ministry.
Your profession as a Christian flows from your relationship with Jesus.
If you want your career to prosper, your relationship with God must prosper.
If you want your marriage to be strong, your relationship with God must be strong.
If you want your business to be great, your relationship with God must be great.
If you want this Christmas to be a Merry Christmas, your relationship with God must be merry.
Leaders, people in authority and position, if you want your nation to be great,
your relationship with God must be great.
Your great love for God will make you great
because whatever we do for God is a reflection of our relationship with God.
It is all about Jesus.
Stop talking about your limited education and start loving Jesus.
Stop complaining that everyone in my family is poor; start loving Jesus.
Stop repeating stories of those who have failed you in the past and start loving Jesus.
Stop pointing fingers at the economy of your nation, the politics of your nation
and start loving Jesus.
Stop meditating on your flaws, weaknesses, failures, frailties and start loving Jesus.
Your great love for God will make you great.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If the love of Christ is in our hearts, the world is under our feet and the sky is our limit.
Our love for Christ will produce this virtue and Christ's love for us will produce this effect upon us.
So brethren, this Christmas, love God above all.
May God bless His Word in the midst of our hearts, in Jesus' name.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 01/02/2019
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 03/13/2019